?Are you ready, kids-
？你们准​​备好了吗，孩子们——
!KIDS: Aye, aye, Captain
!KIDS：是的，是的，队长
.I can't hear you-
.我听不到你说话-
!KIDS: Aye, aye, Captain
!KIDS：是的，是的，队长
THEME SONG: Oh, who lives in
?a pineapple under the sea
主题曲：哦，谁住在
？海底的菠萝
!SpongeBob SquarePants
!海绵宝宝
Absorbent and yellow
.and porous is he
吸水性和黄色
.他是多孔的
!SpongeBob SquarePants
!海绵宝宝
If nautical nonsense
.be something you wish
如果航海废话
.成为你想要的东西
!SpongeBob SquarePants
!海绵宝宝
,Then drop on the deck
!and flop like a fish
,然后落在甲板上
！然后像鱼一样扑通扑通
!SpongeBob SquarePants
!海绵宝宝
?Ready
？准备好
.SpongeBob Squares
.海绵宝宝广场
.SpongeBob SquarePants
.海绵宝宝
!SpongeBob SquarePants
!海绵宝宝
[LAUGHING]
[笑]
!Wow-
！哇-
.It's Sunday, Gary
.今天是星期日，加里
.Guess what's for breakfast
.猜猜早餐吃什么
[MEOWING]
[喵呜]
.That's right
。这是正确的
.A sundae
.圣代
.Whoops
.哎呀
Looks like we're
.out of ice cream
看来我们是
.没有冰淇淋了
Guess I'll have to
.use something else
我想我必须这样做
.使用其他东西
!Ketchup
！番茄酱
[GROANING]
[呻吟]
.Hm
.嗯
.Bananas, cherries
.香蕉、樱桃
.Boring
。无聊的
.Ah, here we go
.啊，我们开始吧
.Onions
.洋葱
?Ready, Gary
准备好了吗，加里
[MEOWING]
[喵呜]
[PLAYING VIOLIN]
[拉小提琴]
.Just one more thing
.还有一件事
!Peanuts
！花生
Gary, our peanuts
.jar is totally empty
加里，我们的花生
.jar 完全是空的
[BURPING]
[打嗝]
.Hm
.嗯
.Wait
。等待
I know one other place
.we can find peanuts
我知道另外一个地方
.我们可以找到花生
Good thing I still
have these peanut
还好我还在
有这些花生
plants growing in
.the windowsill
植物生长在
.窗台
[BUZZING]
[嗡嗡声]
.A little texture never hurt
.一点纹理不会有什么坏处
.There we go
.我们开始吧
This sundae's going
.to taste great
这个圣代要来了
.味道好极了
Aren't you going
?to help me, Gary
你不去吗
？帮助我，加里
?Gary
？加里
.Oh, well
。那好吧
.More for me
.对我来说更多
.Ah
。啊
.Mm
。毫米
.You know what they say, Gary
.你知道他们说什么，加里
.I'm easy like Sunday morning
.我就像周日早上一样轻松
.OK, let's see my to do list
.好的，让我们看看我的待办事项清单
,Go to work, go to work
.go to work, go to work
,上班去上班
.去上班吧，去上班吧
.No, that's not right
.不，那是不对的
.I need the one for Sunday
.我需要周日的一份
.Ah, here we go
.啊，我们开始吧
Say hi to everyone
.in Bikini Bottom
向大家问好
.in 比基尼泳裤
.Hello
。你好
Some people are
.even late on Sunday
有些人是
.即使周日晚些时候
.Hi, Mail Fish
.嗨，邮件鱼
[SNIFFING]
[嗅探]
[WHISTLE BLOWING]
[吹口哨]
.Hi, Mrs. Crossing Guard
.嗨，路口警卫夫人
!Mother of mercy-
！慈悲之母-
[HORN HONKING]
[喇叭鸣响]
[SCREAMING]
[尖叫]
[CRASHING]
[崩溃]
!Oh-
！哦-
!Wow, a parade
！哇，游行
.Hi, parade
.嗨，游行
.Hi, tuba player
.嗨，大号演奏家
.Hi, drummer
.嗨，鼓手
.Hi, guy with the cymbals
.嗨，铙钹家伙
.Hi, trumpeter
.嗨，小号手
.Hi, tambourine girl
.嗨，手鼓女孩
.Hi, timbali man
.嗨，廷巴里人
.Hi, didgeridoo player
.嗨，迪吉里杜管演奏者
.Hi, triangle player
.嗨，三角玩家
.Hi, guy with the kettledrum
.嗨，定音鼓家伙
.Hi, pianist
.嗨，钢琴家
.Hi, guy with the flute
.嗨，吹笛子的家伙
!And hello, Dolly
！你好，多莉
!My leg-
！我的腿-
!Oh, my-
！哦，我的-
[SCREAMING]
[尖叫]
?Was is something I said-
？是我说的-
Something weird
.is going on today
有什么奇怪的
.今天发生
.Everyone's running away from me
.每个人都在逃离我
And now giant
?piles of bubblegum
而现在巨人
？成堆的泡泡糖
?Oh, what next
？哦，接下来做什么
.Hi, SpongeBob-
.嗨，海绵宝宝-
.Oh, hi, Patrick-
.哦，嗨，帕特里克-
.I'm confused
。我很困惑
.Yes, I am-
。我是-
Patrick, everyone is-
.running away from me
帕特里克，每个人都是——
.逃离我的身边
.Watch
。手表
.Hi, building
.嗨，大楼
.I just don't get it
.我只是不明白
.I don't either-
.我也不-
Maybe it's the way
.you're dressed
也许这就是方式
.你穿好了
.Nah-
.不-
.Maybe it's your voice-
.也许这是你的声音-
[LAUGHING]
[笑]
.Good one, Patrick-
.好一个，帕特里克-
Well, maybe it's just-
.because you're ugly
好吧，也许这只是——
.因为你很丑
?Ugly-
？丑陋的-
.You gotta be kidding me
.你一定是在开玩笑吧
.Better try the reflection test-
.最好尝试反射测试-
.Hi-
。你好-
.Ugly-
。丑陋的-
!Oh, no-
！哦，不——
!I can't be ugly
！我不能丑
!I can't be
！我不能
.I can't be ugly
.我不能丑
?Am I ugly
？我很丑吗
[SCREAMING]
[尖叫]
?Am I ugly
？我很丑吗
!My eyes-
！我的眼睛-
!My eyes
！我的眼睛
[GROANING]
[呻吟]
!I'm ugly-
！我很丑-
SpongeBob, can I-
?borrow some bath beads
海绵宝宝，我可以——
？借一些浴珠
[ORGAN MUSIC PLAYING]
[管风琴音乐演奏]
?SpongeBob
?海绵宝宝
.Go-
。去-
.Run away like all the others
.像其他人一样逃跑
No one would want a
.friend as ugly as I am
没有人会想要一个
.朋友和我一样丑
.Sure they would-
.当然他们会-
It makes them feel better
.about the way they look
这让他们感觉更好
.关于他们的外表
.Maybe a story will cheer you up
.也许一个故事会让你高兴起来
".It's called "The Ugly Barnacle
”.它的名字叫“丑陋的藤壶”
Once, there was
.an ugly barnacle
曾经，有
.丑陋的藤壶
He was so ugly
.that everyone died
他太丑了
.每个人都死了
.The end
.结束
.That didn't help at all-
.这根本没有帮助-
?How long
？多久
How long have I
?been ugly, Patrick
我有多久了
？很丑，帕特里克
.As long as I can remember-
.只要我记得-
.You poor ugly thing, you
.你这个可怜又丑陋的东西，你
!Help me-
！帮我-
.I'm so ashamed
.我很羞愧
!I'm spiralling
！我在螺旋上升
.Thanks, Patrick
.谢谢，帕特里克
.It's OK, Patrick
.没关系，帕特里克
.Spiralling over
.螺旋式结束
Just do what I do-
.when I have problems
就做我做的事吧——
.当我遇到问题时
!SCREAMING) Scream)
！尖叫）尖叫）
.Come on, buddy
.来吧，伙计
.I'll help you
.我会帮助你
.OK now, say it
.好吧，现在说吧
.Say it
.说吧
.I can't-
.我不能-
SpongeBob, you're never-
going to feel better
海绵宝宝，你永远不会——
会感觉好一些
until you get this
.thing off your chest
直到你得到这个
.你胸中的事情
.I know, Patrick-
.我知道，帕特里克-
.Say it-
.说吧-
.Say it
.说吧
.I'm ugly-
.我很丑-
?You're ugly and what-
？你很丑还有什么-
?Square-
？正方形-
.No-
。不-
.Proud
。自豪的
.I'm ugly, and I'm proud-
.我很丑，但我很骄傲-
!Good-
！好的-
.Say it louder
.大声说
.I'm ugly, and I'm proud-
.我很丑，但我很骄傲-
.Louder-
.大声-
!I'm ugly, and I'm proud-
！我很丑，但我很骄傲-
!PATRICK: Louder
！帕特里克：大声点
SPONGEBOB: I'm
!ugly, and I'm proud
海绵宝宝：我是
！丑陋，但我很自豪
SCREAMING) I am)
!ugly, and I'm proud
尖叫）我是）
！丑陋，但我很自豪
!I'm ugly, and I'm proud
！我很丑，但我很骄傲
?Is that what he calls it-
？这就是他所说的——
[PANTING]
[气喘吁吁]
!That felt great-
！那感觉太棒了——
.I feel empowered
.我感到自己充满力量
?So what do you want to do now-
？那么你现在想做什么-
.I don't know-
。我不知道-
?How about a movie
？看电影怎么样
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[音乐播放]
.Pardon me
。对不起
.Ugly sponge coming through
.丑陋的海绵过来了
.People respect self-esteem-
.人们尊重自尊-
.Hi-
。你好-
I'm very ugly, but you should
.enjoy the movie anyway
我很丑，但你应该
.无论如何，请欣赏这部电影
.Excuse me, sir
.对不起，先生
I hope my horrible ugliness
.won't be a distraction to you
我希望我可怕的丑陋
.不会让你分心
.Not at all, boy-
.一点也不，男孩-
[SCREAMING]
[尖叫]
[RUNNING]
[跑步]
Don't worry about-
.him, SpongeBob
别担心——
.他，海绵宝宝
--He's just a
——他只是一个
[CRYING]
[哭泣]
.SpongeBob
.海绵宝宝
?SpongeBob, what's wrong
海绵宝宝，怎么了
[SNIFFING]
[嗅探]
.I can't do this, Patrick-
.我不能这么做，帕特里克-
I've tried, and I've
tried, but-- I'm
我已经尝试过了，而且我已经
尝试过了，但是——我
not always as
.confident as I look
并不总是像
.我看起来很自信
Maybe I better just
.go back and hide
也许我最好只是
.回去躲起来
?What is wrong with you people-
？你们怎么了-
Afraid to look
?ugliness in the face
不敢看
? 脸色丑陋
!Well, here
！嗯，这里
!Look at it
！看看它
?It's ugly, isn't it
？很丑，不是吗？
!You look at it
！你看一下
.Hello-
。你好-
!You look at it-
！你看看——
.Hi-
。你好-
!Look at it-
！看看它——
!Look at it
！看看它
Look at it! (SCREAMING) I
!want all of you to look at it
看看它！ （尖叫）我
！想让大家都看看
[SCREAMING]
[尖叫]
.They all ran away, Patrick-
.他们都逃跑了，帕特里克-
I bet there's no-
.line at the snack bar
我敢打赌没有-
.在小吃店排队
?Hello
？你好
.They must be on break
.他们一定是在休息
.Oh, wait, Patrick-
.哦，等等，帕特里克-
.I just remembered
.我刚刚想起来
I've got some of my peanut
.onion sundae we can share
我有一些花生
.洋葱圣代我们可以分享
.That looks great-
.看起来很棒-
[SLURPING]
[啜饮]
.Ah
。啊
[RATTLING]
[嘎嘎作响]
.Oh
。哦
.I gotta go to the restroom
.我得去趟洗手间
.I'm out of soap
.我没有肥皂了
--Could I borrow
--可以借吗
!Stay back-
！退后-
--Uh, I just want some-
--呃，我只是想要一些-
.Here-
。这里-
.Here's my money
.这是我的钱
.Take it
.拿走吧
.Take it, and go away
.拿着它，然后走开
.My hands aren't that dirty-
.我的手没那么脏-
.Hey
。嘿
Hey, do you guys want
?to hear a bathroom joke
嘿，你们想要吗
？听一个浴室笑话
[GAGGING]
[作呕]
?You trying to kill us-
？你想杀了我们-
.Oh, that's ridiculous-
.哦，这太荒谬了-
!Oh-
！哦-
!Oh
！哦
!I got the ugly
！我丑了
Patrick, is-
?everything OK in here
帕特里克，是——
？这里一切都好
[CRYING]
[哭泣]
What are you doing
?in there, Patrick
你在做什么
？在那里，帕特里克
?Wouldn't you like to know-
？你不想知道吗-
And why is that-
?bag on your head
而这是为什么——
？头上的袋子
?Why-
？为什么-
.Oh, no reason
.哦，没有理由
!Except you gave me the ugly
！除了你给了我丑陋的
[SCREAMING]
[尖叫]
?Well, what am I going to do
？那么，我该怎么办
I can't go out
.looking like this
我不能出去
.看起来像这样
Just remember what-
.we talked about
只要记住什么——
.我们谈论过
.There's power in pride
.骄傲是有力量的
That may be fine-
for you, but I was
这样或许还好——
为了你，但我是
.one of the beautiful people
.美丽的人之一
!Now look at me
！现在看着我
!I'm almost as ugly as you
！我几乎和你一样丑
[SNIFFING]
[嗅探]
I always thought, if I
,was as ugly as that guy
我一直想，如果我
,和那家伙一样丑陋
.I don't know what I would do
.我不知道我会做什么
.Patrick-
.帕特里克-
?What's my mom going to say-
？我妈妈会说什么-
.Patrick-
.帕特里克-
Oh, my gosh, if my-
.sister finds out
哦，天哪，如果我——
.姐姐发现了
.Patrick-
.帕特里克-
Oh, wait, I don't-
.have a sister
哦，等等，我不-
.有一个妹妹
,If the bank-- oh, I mean
it's one thing if you have
，如果银行——哦，我是说
如果你有的话这是一回事
bad shoes or even
--bad hair, but
鞋子不好甚至
——头发不好，但是
!Patrick-
！帕特里克-
.You're not ugly
.你并不丑
.Your breath stinks
.你的呼吸很臭
.Really bad
.真的很糟糕
[SIGHING]
[叹息]
.What a relief-
.真是松了口气——
[SCREAMING]
[尖叫]
,Gah, barnacles, Patrick-
?what did you eat
，嘎，藤壶，帕特里克-
?你吃了什么
,Oh, some roast beef-
.some chicken, a pizza
，哦，一些烤牛肉-
.一些鸡肉，一个披萨
.No, I mean, just the morning-
.不，我是说，只是早上-
,Some roast beef-
.some chicken, a pizza
,一些烤牛肉-
.一些鸡肉，一个披萨
?What else-
？还有什么-
Well, I had some-
.of your sundae
嗯，我有一些-
.你的圣代
.Sundae-
.圣代-
Patrick, my sundae
.gave us rancid breath
帕特里克，我的圣代
.给我们带来腐臭的气息
?What do you mean-
？你是什么意思-
.I mean, we're not ugly-
.我的意思是，我们并不丑-
.We just stink
.我们只是臭
?Stink-
？臭-
[CHEERING]
[欢呼]
!We stink-
！我们很臭-
!We stink
！我们很臭
!Oh, guess what, Squidward-
！哦，你猜怎么着，章鱼哥——
!We stink-
！我们很臭-
!Ah, yeah-
！啊，是啊——
!Yes
！是的
!I stink-
！我很臭-
!PATRICK: I reek
！帕特里克：我很臭
!SPONGEBOB: Smell me
！海绵宝宝：闻闻我的味道
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[音乐播放]
!MR. KRABS: Attention
！先生。螃蟹：注意
!Attention
！注意力
All Krusty Krew
!employees, attention
所有库斯蒂·克鲁
！员工注意了
Get the anchors out of your
.pants and report to me office
把锚从你的
.裤子并向我办公室报告
.That will be all
.这就是全部
I have an important
.announcement to make
我有一个重要的
.公告
!Ooh-
！哦-
!Hooray
！万岁
!The new spatulas are here
！新的抹刀来了
.Sit down, boy-
.坐下，男孩-
.There's no new spatulas
.没有新的抹刀
.How disappointing-
.多么令人失望-
You men know me-
.daughter, Pearl
你们认识我-
.女儿，珍珠
.She's growing up fast
.她长得很快
It seems like it
was just yesterday
好像是这样
就在昨天
I was teaching
.her how to breach
我在教课
.她如何突破
.Me mammalian angel
.Me 哺乳动物天使
[CLEARING THROAT]
[清嗓子]
Anyway, uh, so she's
going to be working
无论如何，呃，所以她是
将要工作
.here during her summer vacation
.她暑假期间在这里
She's got a lot of
fresh ideas to bring
她有很多
带来新的想法
.in some hungry customers
.在一些饥饿的顾客中
[DOOR OPENING]
[开门]
!PEARL: Hello
！珍珠：你好
?Daddy
?爸爸
!There she blows-
！她在那里吹——
SpongeBob, do you-
?realise what this means
海绵宝宝，你——
？明白这意味着什么
.No new spatulas-
.没有新的抹刀-
!No-
！不-
It means some bratty
teenager's coming
意思就是有些猥琐的意思
少年来了
.in here to tell us what to do
.在这里告诉我们该怎么做
.We can't have that
.我们不能这样
?We have seniority, right
？我们有资历吧
.Right-
。正确的-
So we'll work together to-
.protect our pathetic positions
所以我们将共同努力——
.保护我们可怜的地位
.Okie dokie, Squidward-
.Okie dokie，章鱼哥-
And then we'll get
.those new spatulas
然后我们会得到
.那些新的抹刀
.All right, men-
.好吧，伙计们-
.Say hello to me Pearl
.向我问好珍珠
.Hello, Pole-
.你好，波兰人-
.Hi, guys-
。嗨，大家好-
It makes me jolly-
as a roger to finally
这让我很高兴——
作为罗杰最后
have you aboard the
.family business
你登上了吗
.家族企业
Great, Dad, because I-
.have so many new ideas
太好了，爸爸，因为我——
.有很多新想法
.I can smell the money already-
.我已经闻到钱的味道了-
I'll be in my office
.if you need me
我会在我的办公室
.如果你需要我
?What's in the box-
?盒子里有什么-
.It's a surprise-
.这是一个惊喜-
.I like surprises-
.我喜欢惊喜-
.Great-
。伟大的-
.Then close your eyes
.然后闭上眼睛
!I'm ready-
！我准备好了-
.Well, I like it so far-
.嗯，到目前为止我很喜欢-
!Ta-da-
！哒哒哒
[GASPING]
[喘气]
It's the new Krusty
.Krew uniform
这是新的库斯蒂
.克鲁制服
[LAUGHING]
[笑]
.I designed it myself
.我自己设计的
.OK, this is it, SpongeBob-
.好吧，就是这样，海绵宝宝-
Now tell her how you really
.feel about that uniform
现在告诉她你真的如何
.感觉一下那件制服
.OK, Squidward-
.好吧，章鱼哥-
Pearl, this is the
!greatest uniform ever
珍珠，这是
！有史以来最伟大的制服
.Fish paste-
.鱼酱-
Oh, SpongeBob, you-
.look so adorable
噢，海绵宝宝，你——
.看起来很可爱
.I could just eat you up
.我可以吃掉你
Sorry, Pearl, this-
.item's not on the menu
对不起，珀尔，这个——
.item 不在菜单上
Well, I didn't think it-
,was possible, SpongeBob
嗯，我没想到——
，有可能，海绵宝宝
but you look even more
.ridiculous than usual
但你看起来更
.比平常更可笑
PEARL: Don't be
.jealous, Uncle Squiddy
珍珠：别这样
.嫉妒，鱿鱼叔叔
.I made one for you, too
.我也给你做了一个
!Don't bother-
！别打扰-
.Only a fool would wear that
.只有傻子才会穿那个
.Avast, ye shipmates-
.Avast，你们这些船友们-
Don't these just
?shiver your timbers
难道这些只是
？颤抖你的木材
.Get that suit on, sailor
.穿上那套衣服，水手
.It's already been paid for
.已经付款了
.Rage-
。愤怒-
.Fury
。愤怒
.Irritation
.刺激
.Humiliation
。屈辱
.Squidward is such a barnacle-
.章鱼哥就是这样的藤壶-
.A stick in the sand-
.沙子里的一根棍子-
.But not you, SpongeBob-
.但不是你，海绵宝宝-
.You are full of style
.你风情万种
?Me-
？我-
?Really
？真的
.Totally, SB-
.总而言之，SB-
.You ooze fashion
.你散发着时尚气息
And I've got some
completely coro
我有一些
完全科罗
.concepts for this old joint
.这个老联合的概念
And I'm going to need someone
with your kind of talent
我需要有人
以你的才华
.to help me
.帮助我
Well, I have been-
trying to get Mr. Krabs
嗯，我一直——
试图找到蟹老板
to make some
.changes around here
做一些
.这里的变化
Why, with my girlish instincts-
,and your, um, sponginess
为什么，以我少女的本能——
，还有你的，嗯，海绵状
we'll turn this worn out lunch
.waggon into a teenage paradise
我们将把这顿破烂的午餐
.waggon 进入青少年天堂
SpongeBob, what do
--you like better
海绵宝宝，做什么
——你更喜欢
the Kutie Krab or
?the Kooky Krab
蟹蟹库蒂 (Kutie Krab) 或
？古怪的螃蟹
?For what-
？为了什么-
.Dare I ask
.我敢问吗
.The new name for our new look-
.我们新面貌的新名称-
I mean, the Krusty
.Krab has got to go
我的意思是，库斯蒂
.蟹蟹得走了
Who wants to eat at a
?place they think is crusty
谁想在一个
？他们认为很硬的地方
.Blech
.布莱希
Well, sure, it's-
,a terrible name
嗯，当然，这是——
,一个可怕的名字
.but this is a terrible place
.但这是一个可怕的地方
Therefore, the name
.should be left alone
因此，名称
.应该单独留下
?Right, SpongeBob
？对吧，海绵宝宝
!I got it-
！我得到了它-
?How about the Chaotic Crab
?混沌蟹怎么样
.Hm-
.嗯-
?How about the Kissy Krab
?吻西蟹怎么样
.The King Krab-
.蟹王-
.The Candy Crab-
.糖果蟹-
The Cool Crab or-
.the Cowboy Crab
酷螃蟹或-
.牛仔蟹
.The Curly Crab
.卷毛蟹
.The Creepy Crab
.令人毛骨悚然的螃蟹
.The Killer Krab
.杀手蟹
[GASPING]
[喘气]
.No-
。不-
.You're right-
。你说得对-
.Too scary
.太吓人了
.Hm
.嗯
!The Kuddly Krab-
！可爱的螃蟹-
.Aww
.哇哦
[LAUGHING]
[笑]
[GROANING]
[呻吟]
It's a shame old man-
.Krab sold the Krusty Krab
老头真是可惜了——
.Krab 卖掉了 Krusty Krab
.It's a darn shame-
.真是太可惜了-
Hey, lady, do you
know where we can
嘿，女士，你是吗？
知道我们可以在哪里
get something to
?eat around here
得到一些东西
?在这附近吃饭
!That's it I quit-
！就这样我放弃了-
[WHISTLE BLOWING]
[吹口哨]
Finally a cool place for teens-
.to just, you know, hang out
终于有一个适合青少年的好地方了-
.只是，你知道，闲逛
.Pearl, you're a genius-
.Pearl，你真是个天才-
,All these young
.hip new customers
,所有这些年轻人
.hip新客户
.Phooey on Squidward
.Phooey 谈《章鱼哥》
.He can't keep up with the times
.他跟不上时代
.You're a true visionary, Pearl
.你真是一个有远见的人，珍珠
.Thank you, SpongeBob-
.谢谢你，海绵宝宝-
.I do have 20/20 vision
.我确实有20/20的视力
Well, hip people-
.have to eat, too
嗯，时髦的人们——
.也得吃饭
.Back to the grill
.回到烤架
,The customers may be hot
.but my grill is hotter
,顾客可能会很热
.但我的烤架更热
[HISSING]
[嘶嘶声]
.PEARL: SpongeBob, order up
.PEARL：海绵宝宝，订购
.Two salads-
.两份沙拉-
.Never heard of it
.没听说过
.I gotta stay hip
.我必须保持时髦
I don't want to end up
.like silly old Squidward
我不想结束
.就像愚蠢的老章鱼哥
But what in the name of Davy
?Jones's locker is a salad
但以戴维的名义
？琼斯的储物柜是沙拉
.Here you go
。干得好
.Two salads
.两份沙拉
.Ew, gross-
.呃，恶心-
.Those aren't salads
.那些不是沙拉
.Take those back
.把那些拿回来
Remove the bun, the
.patty and the condiments
取出馒头，将
.肉饼和调味品
But that leaves just-
.lettuce and tomato
但这只剩下——
.生菜和番茄
.Exactly-
。确切地-
.All right-
。好的-
.OK
。好的
.No buns
.没有包子
.That's hip
.那很时髦
.No patties
.没有肉饼
.Happening
.发生的事情
Oh, yeah, that's definitely
.the coolest meal I ever saw
哦，是的，这绝对是
.我见过的最酷的一餐
.This is so cool-
.这太酷了-
.Two salads-
.两份沙拉-
.That was awful
.那太糟糕了
I hope I never
have to tear apart
我希望我永远不会
必须撕开
a perfectly good Krabby
.Patty ever again
一只完美的蟹蟹
.帕蒂再次
I don't think my
.heart can take it
我不认为我的
.心可以承受
[SCREAMING]
[尖叫]
?Where's the grill
？烤架在哪里
,Come on, SpongeBob-
.you're a hip guy
，来吧，海绵宝宝-
.你是个时髦的人
You know fried foods
.are O-U-T, out
你知道油炸食品吗
.are O-U-T, 出
.Uh, right on-
.呃，对了-
Check out this new-
.menu I came up with
看看这个新的——
.menu 我想出了
.Salad and tea-
.沙拉和茶-
But where are the
?Krabby patties
但是哪里有
?蟹肉饼
.Oh, silly, those aren't hip-
.哦，愚蠢的，那些不时髦-
Oh, you won't be needing
.that thing anymore
哦，你不会需要
.那件事了
[SCREAMING]
[尖叫]
--B--b--b-
PEARL: I've got something more
.fun for you to do, anyway
珍珠：我还有更多东西
.无论如何，这对你来说很有趣
?Hey, buddy, you need a ride-
？嘿，伙计，你需要搭车-
I was just on my way to
.the big doofus convention
我正要去
.大傻瓜大会
[LAUGHING]
[笑]
.This is humiliating-
.这是耻辱-
.I'm a fry cook, darn it
.我是一名油炸厨师，该死的
,You can take away my spatula
but when you take away
,你可以拿走我的锅铲
但当你拿走时
my dignity, that's
!when I get mad
我的尊严，就是
！当我生气的时候
I'm going to march right into
Mr. Krabs's office and tell him
我要直接进军
蟹老板的办公室并告诉他
.this is just too much
.这实在是太多了
.Oh
。哦
[GROANING]
[呻吟]
.OK, SpongeBob, you can do this
.好吧，海绵宝宝，你可以做到的
.Come on
。快点
?Mr. Krabs, could I talk to you
？先生。蟹蟹，我可以和你谈谈吗
.Come on in, me boy-
.进来吧，我的孩子-
.Have a seat
.请坐
.Thanks, Mr. Krabs-
.谢谢，蟹老板-
Don't you just-
?love me new office
难道你只是——
？爱我的新办公室
.Pearlie designed it for me
.Pearlie 为我设计的
Mr. Krabs, uh, I think-
.we've got a problem
螃蟹先生，呃，我想——
.我们遇到了问题
Isn't that the neatest-
?40 chair you ever sat in$
这不是最简洁的吗——
?40 张你曾经坐过的椅子$
Sure, Mr. Krabs, but-
.I've got some bad news
当然，蟹老板先生，但是——
.我有一些坏消息
How about my cuddly-
?executive bunny
我的可爱呢——
?行政兔子
Reduces stress for only
.five easy payment of $9.95
减轻压力仅
.五轻松付款9.95美元
Mr. Krabs, Pearl is-
.ruining the Krusty Krab
蟹老板先生，珍珠是——
.毁了蟹堡王
?What-
？什么-
Why, Peal is saving
.the Krustry Krab
为什么，皮尔在拯救
.Krustry Krab
.I mean, the Kuddly Krab
.我的意思是，可爱的螃蟹
What would we do without
these beautiful $20 sea
如果没有的话我们该怎么办
这些美丽的 20 美元大海
?unicorn wall hangers
?独角兽壁挂架
How could we have ever survived
?without these $35 heart lights
我们怎么可能活下来
？没有这些 35 美元的心形灯
How could we go on wit a sea
?fern on every last table
我们怎样才能继续与大海相处
？每张桌子上都有蕨类植物
!It's hip
！很时髦
!It's coro
！这是科罗
!It's-- it's losing money
！这——正在赔钱
Ah, you're right, SpongeBob, but
.I can't fire me pride and joy
啊，你是对的，海绵宝宝，但是
.我无法激发我的骄傲和喜悦
It would break her
.fragile little heart
这会让她崩溃
.脆弱的小心脏
?What am I going to do
？我要做什么
[CRYING]
[哭泣]
.There, there, Mr. Krabs-
.那里，那里，蟹老板-
.I'm sure there's another way
.我确信还有另一种方法
.That's it, boy-
.就是这样，男孩-
?What's it-
？这是什么-
.You could fire her-
.你可以解雇她-
.It's OK if she hates you
.如果她恨你也没关系
.That's not what I said, sir-
.那不是我说的，先生-
.Great then, it's all settled-
.那就太好了，一切都解决了-
.You fire Pearlie
.你解雇了Pearlie
.I'll hide in the office
.我会躲在办公室里
.Totally rude, SpongeBob-
.完全粗鲁，海绵宝宝-
Pearl, could I see you in-
?the kitchen for a second
珀尔，我可以见你吗——
？厨房一会儿
.Sure, SpongeBob-
.当然，海绵宝宝-
VOICEOVER) How am I)-
?going to break it to her
画外音）我怎么样）-
？要打破它给她
.I've never fired anyone before
.我以前从未解雇过任何人
.Well, I just got to say it
.好吧，我只是想说
.Pearl, you're fired
.Pearl，你被解雇了
.OK, here it goes
.好的，就这样
[INHALING]
[吸气]
[CRYING]
[哭泣]
.Oh, SpongeBob-
.哦，海绵宝宝-
.I can't take it anymore
.我再也受不了了
.Nothing I do is working
.我所做的一切都不起作用
.Sure, it is, Pearl-
.当然，是的，珍珠-
Look at all the hip, young
.people eating salads
看看都翘臀了，年轻
.人们吃沙拉
.No-
。不-
?Don't you get it
？你不明白吗？
I've been trying to get
.fired since day one
我一直在努力得到
.从第一天起就被解雇
I was only pretending to like
.this place to please Daddy
我只是假装喜欢
.这个地方可以取悦爸爸
This job is cutting majorly
.into my social life
这项工作主要是削减
.进入我的社交生活
?Oh, SpongeBob, what should I do
？哦，海绵宝宝，我该怎么办
.I've got it-
.我明白了-
.I could pretend to fire you
.我可以假装解雇你
I'll take the heat from
.old man Krabs later
我会带走热量
.蟹老爷子后来
Gosh, you'd really-
?do that for me
天哪，你真的会——
？为我做那个
.You're a great pal, SpongeBob
.海绵宝宝，你是个好朋友
?How can I ever thank you
？我该如何感谢你
Stop trying to-
.break me in half
别再试图——
.把我分成两半
.Deal-
。交易-
.Oh, boy
.哦，男孩
.WHISPERING) OK, Pearl)-
.耳语）好吧，珀尔）-
We've got to make
.this convincing
我们必须做
.这令人信服
Pearl, I need to
.have a word with you
珍珠，我需要
.和你说句话
[CRYING]
[哭泣]
.Oh, no-
.哦，不-
.Here it goes
.就这样
I don't know if I
.can bear to listen
我不知道我是否
.可以耐听
It's not that you haven't-
.done a good job around here
这并不是说你没有——
.这里做得很好
--It's just that
——仅此而已
Oh, don't be too-
.hard on her now
哦，别太-
.现在对她很严厉
?Why does it have to be this way
？为什么一定要这样
.It's for the best
.这是最好的
Well, we feel it might be in-
--everybody's best interest if
嗯，我们觉得它可能是在——
——每个人的最大利益如果
.I can't let him do this-
.我不能让他这样做-
?Huh
？哈
!Get on with it, SpongeBob
！继续吧，海绵宝宝
.Pearl, you're fire-
.珍珠，你很火-
[SCREAMING]
[尖叫]
.Thanks, SpongeBob-
.谢谢，海绵宝宝-
.Come on, gang
.来吧，帮派
!The mall waits
！商场等待
!Hey, Mr. Krabs, I did it-
！嘿，蟹老板，我做到了——
[SCREAMING]
[尖叫]
.Oh, Pearlie-
.哦，皮尔莉-
?Is that a 20
？那是20
Oh, SpongeBob, how
could we have done
哦，海绵宝宝，怎么了
我们可以做吗
such a thing to me
?own flesh and blood
对我来说是这样的事
?自己的骨肉
.There, there, Mr. Krabs-
.那里，那里，蟹老板-
.Pearl took it just fine
.Pearl 接受得很好
In fact, she seemed
.kind of happy
事实上，她看起来
.有点高兴
?Really-
？真的-
She's off to bigger-
.and better things
她要去更大的地方——
.以及更好的事情
That's me girl, tough as-
.nails, just like her old man
这就是我，女孩，坚强——
.指甲，就像她老人家一样
But how am I going to get my
?money back for all this stuff
但我怎样才能得到我的
？所有这些东西的退款
.Hm-
.嗯-
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[音乐播放]
!Woo
！呜
!Yeah
！是的
[LAUGHING]
[笑]
[YELLING]
[大喊]
!All right
！好的
?Isn't this great, Gary
？这不是很棒吗，加里
And it only cost me
.one year's salary
而这仅仅花费了我
.一年的工资
[MEOWING]
[喵呜]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[音乐播放]